This holiday expect the unexpected
Hogfather is a fantasy, tv movie film directed by Vadim Jean.
It's the night before Hogswatch, usually a time of joy on Discworld, but there
are suspicious going-on and the criminal underworld is abuzz.
The beloved Hogfather - the jolly bearer of glee and
pork-related gifts for children everywhere - has vanished.
Suddenly, Discworld's entire mythical system is under threat.
The fate of this magical time rests in the hands of a very motley group: A band of wizards headed up by a mystical university president named Mustrum Ridcully (Joss Ackland), a loyal
manservant called Albert (David Jason), a level-headed governess called Susan Sto Heilt (Michelle Dockery), and her grandfather, who happens to be - Death (Marnix van den Broeke).
Albert, played by David Jason.
Teatime, played by Marc Warren.
Susan, played by Michelle Dockery.
Lord Downey, played by David Warner.
Vernon Crumley, played by Tony Robinson.
Mr. Sideney, played by Nigel Planer.
Hogfather is the 20th Discworld novel by Terry Pratchett,
and a 1997 British Fantasy Award nominee.
It was first released in 1996 and published by Victor Gollancz.
It came in 137th place in The Big Read, a BBC survey of the most loved British books of
all time, making it one of fifteen books by Pratchett in the Top 200.
The book focuses on the absence of the Hogfather, a mythical creature akin to Father Christmas, who
grants children's wishes on Hogswatchnight (December 32) and brings them presents.
While Death attempts to fill in for the Hogfather, his granddaughter
Susan Sto Helit tries to find and rescue the Hogfather.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book,
santa claus, disguise, death, christmas.